[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&GT；&GT；Kyle：是时候进入一些真正的大脑弯曲的东西了。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Time to move in to some really brain bending stuff.
如果你认为我们讨论的东西是脑筋急转弯，
If you thought the stuff that we went over was brain bending,
系好安全带。
buckle up your seat belt.
并发。
Concurrency.
这就是我们一直在讨论的整个研讨会。
That's what we've been talking about this entire workshop.
这个穷人对我所说的并发的定义是什么？
What was the poor man's definition for what I meant by concurrency?
基本上，管理流量控制。
Basically, managing the flow control.
管理所有这些正在发生的事情
Managing all these things that are happening and
按正确的顺序对事物作出反应。
responding to things in the proper order.
我们知道，当只有一个请求和一个响应时，承诺就会起作用。
We know that Promises work when there's a single request and a single response.
当我们即将到来的信息来源，
What happens when the source of our information that's coming,
实际上是不断出现的信息流？
is actually a repeated stream of information that's coming?
例如，我们能否将承诺连接到事件流中？
Can we wire Promises into an event stream, for example?
因为坦率地说，如果我们真的看它，大部分
Because frankly speaking, if we really look at it, most of
在我们的程序中发生的异步性实际上是面向事件的。
the asynchronicity that's happening in our programs is actually event oriented.
我们所有的UI几乎都是面向事件的。
All of our UI is almost entirely event oriented.
这是来自服务器的事件。
It's events coming from the server.
这是来自用户的事件。
It's events coming from the user.
我们到处都有活动。
We have events everywhere.
一旦你开始尝试插入承诺，你可能会开始看到一些问题。
Soon as you start trying to plug Promises in you might start to see some issues.
让我试着说明一下。
Let me try to illustrate that for a moment.
假设我的页面上有一个按钮
Let's say that I had a button on my page and
我想通过承诺的方式来表示对该按钮的点击。
I wanted to represent the click of that button by way of a promise.
我已经知道我可以构建一个承诺，就像我在第一行所做的那样。
I already know I can construct a promise like I'm doing on line 1.
我可以在里面设置我的点击处理程序。
And I can set up my click handler inside of it.
我有按钮点点击。
I have button dot click.
我做了一些额外的逻辑只是为了说明有额外的步骤
And I'm doing some extra logic just to illustrate that there's extra steps that
我们可能会使用，我要测试它的类名，如果它
we might use, I'm going to test its class name and if it
匹配那个正则表达式FUBAR，然后我要解决这个承诺。
matches that regular expression FUBAR then I'm going to resolve the Promise.
否则我会拒绝这个承诺。
Otherwise I'm going to reject the Promise.
然后在我的程序中的其他地方，
And then down somewhere else in my program,
第13行表示我的程序中的不同位置，
line 13 represents a different place in my program,
我将通过打印出任何被点击的内容来回应这一承诺。
I'm going to respond to that Promise by printing out whatever was clicked on.
现在的精神是每次我点击按钮，
Now the spirit of this is that every time I click on the button,
我会得到我打印出来的，或者如果我点击了一个按钮，
I'm going to get either that I printed it out or if I clicked a button that,
如果它与FUBAR匹配，我将打印出一个className，但是
I'm going to print out a className if it matched FUBAR but
如果我点击一个没有这个功能的按钮，什么都不会发生。
if I clicked a button that didn't have that, nothing would happen.
这就是它的精神。
That's the spirit of it.
有人发现这个代码有问题吗？
Does anybody spot a problem with this code?
怎么了？
What?
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：它只会发射一次。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: It's only gonna fire once.
&gt；&gt；Kyle：承诺只能解决一次。
&gt;&gt; Kyle: Promises can only be resolved once.
第一次单击按钮时，无论是哪个按钮，
The very first time you click a button, whichever button it is,
它将解决或拒绝承诺。
it's going to resolve or reject the Promise.
每次当你点击按钮的时候，什么都不会发生。
And every time else when you click the button, nothing's gonna happen.
哦，我们该怎么办？
Uh-oh, what do we do?
我们如何使用承诺，我们已经建立了自己的承诺和发电机。
How do we use Promises, we've built ourselves up to Promises and generators.
我们已经给自己提供了几层更高阶的抽象。
We've given ourselves several layers of higher order abstractions.
但现在我们面临着一件极其常见的事情，即将发生在我们的
But now we're faced with an extremely common thing that's gonna happen in our
对事件作出响应的程序重复正在发生的事情和
programs that is responding to events repeated things that are happening and
突如其来的承诺似乎分崩离析。
all of sudden Promises seem to fall apart.
我们该怎么办？
What do we do?
嗯，你可以做的一件事就是倒置。
Well, one thing you might do is to invert.
你可以说，而不是创造我的承诺和
You might say instead of creating my Promise and
然后我的按钮处理程序在里面做相反的事情。
then my button handler inside do it the other way around.
制作我的按钮处理程序，单击处理程序，然后在内部创建承诺。
Make my button handler, click handler and then create a Promise inside.
接下来会发生的是我会得到一个全新的承诺
What's gonna happen here is I'm gonna get a whole new Promise for
发射的每个事件。
each event that's fired.
听起来不错。
That sounds great.
除了为什么？
Except, why?
因为一旦通风口已经被发射，
Because once the vents already been fired,
那么这里的承诺的目的是什么。
then what's the purpose of the Promise here.
你看到我在做什么了吗？
You see what I'm doing?
我立即解决了一个承诺，然后立即在上面打一个点。
I'm immediately resolving a Promise ,and then immediately calling a dot then on it.
这有多大意义？
How much sense does that make?
不过，还有更深层次的原因，因为我们真正做的事情
There's something even deeper though, because what we've really done when we
倒过来，我们做了一个简单的小把戏，我把它倒过来
inverted, we made that little simple trick where I inverted it and
我在另一个里面做了一个，而不是反过来。
I did one inside the other instead of the other way around.
现在我们已经合并了我们的关注点分离。
Now we have conflated our separation of concerns.
在前面的代码中，我可以巧妙地设置
In the previous code, subtly I was able to set up
我的来源在一个位置，并有我的回应。
my source in one location and have my response to it.
我能够订阅和
I was able to subscribe and
我有我的来源，它在不同的位置，我的应用程序。
I have my source to it in a different location of my application.
这是两个独立的功能，但当我倒置时，猜猜发生了什么？
Those are two separate capabilities, but when I invert, guess what's happened?
我必须在同一地点设置源和订阅。
I have to set up the source and the subscription all in the same spot.
我把这两种责任混为一谈。
I have conflated those two responsibilities together.
而你必须通过一大堆的圈子才能得到那些承诺
And you gonna have to jump through a whole bunch of hoops to get those Promises
超出您的单击处理程序。
out of your click handler.
每次他开枪，如果你需要那些承诺在其他地方回应
Every time he fired if you need those Promises to respond in other places
你必须将它们保存到某个共享闭包变量中，或者
you're gonna have to save them off into some shared closure variable or
一些荒谬的事情。
some ridiculous thing.
突然之间你会回到过去，回到开始的时候
And all of a sudden you're going to be way back, right back at the beginning all
同样的怪异和难以理解的代码问题。
the same problems of weirdness and hard to understand code.
我们马上就看到了至少是他们自己的承诺，
Right off the bat we see that Promises at least by themselves,
在一个以事件为导向的世界里不能很好地建模。
are not going to model well in an event oriented world.
我们需要更好的东西。
We're going to need something better.
现在你可以观察到
Now you could observe that
实际上，这根本不是一组异步的步骤。
actually that wasn't fundamentally an asynchronous set of steps anyway.
我们可以回到对我们来说更熟悉的事情，比如列表
And we could fall back to things that are a little more familiar to us like a list
我将事件放入数组的上下文，就像我在3，3和
context where I put my event into an array as I'm doing on 3 three and
然后我调用map、约简和过滤器。
then I call maps and reduces and filters.
你可能会回到同步编程的思维模式
You might go back to a synchronous programming mindset and
说，谁在乎诺言。
say, who cares about the promise.
但我们基本上还是有一个倒置的系统，
But we've still fundamentally got an inverted system here,
其中必须将对事件的响应与事件的设置合并。
where the response to the event has to be conflated with the setup for the event.
我们有生产者和消费者在同一地点。
We have producer and consumer in the same spot.
这不是我们想要的。
And that's not what we want.
我们需要一些东西来弥合差距，以便我们可以将这些担忧分开。
We need something to bridge the gap so that we can separate those concerns.